-==www.RagBear.com==- 福尔摩斯探案集  第1季第1集
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
波希米亚丑闻案
A Scandal In Bohemia
逮个正着
Got you!
喂 等等
Now look here...
可是夫人
But mum!
关窗 约翰
Close the window, John.
夏洛克福尔摩斯始终称呼她为那位女人
To Sherlock Holmes, she was always "the woman,"
美丽的艾琳艾德勒 留在他模糊朦胧的记忆中
the beautiful Irena Adler of dubious and questionable memory.
(贝克街)
Baker Street
我们开始插手艾琳艾德勒案之时
At the time of our involvement in the Irena Adler case,
福尔摩斯和我在贝克街
Holmes and I had been sharing rooms in Baker Street
共居多年了
for some years.
因为行医 我离家去乡间
My practice had caused me to be absent in the country
小住了几日
for several days.
照例 不管离开福尔摩斯多久
As usual, after leaving Holmes for any length of time,
每当回家 我都为他的情绪担忧
I returned filled with apprehension as to his mood.
你好 哈德森夫人
Oh, hello, Mrs. Hudson.
华生医生 瞧瞧你 都湿透了
Dr. Watson, just look at you, half soaked to the skin!
那就对了
Yes, well, I am not surprised,
我在瓢泼大雨中站了20分钟
I have just spent 20 minutes standing in the pouring rain
就为等辆马车
waiting for a cab.
当心你的旧伤
It won't do that old wound of yours any good
医生 淋这么湿
getting so wet, Doctor.
我知道
I know.
大衣和帽子给我
I'll just take this coat and your hat
一定要好好烘干
and see that they're properly dried.
哈德森太太 我饿了一天了
Mrs. Hudson, I haven't eaten all day.
真希望马上开饭
I do hope supper will be up very soon.
这可难说
That's very doubtful.
不知福尔摩斯先生怎么了
I don't know what's come over Mr. Holmes,
他好像紧张得要命
he seems to be all on edge.
等他叫我  再送晚饭上去
I'm not to bring up supper until I'm called.
他下的命令
Those are his orders.
谢谢你 哈德森太太
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson.
我亲爱的福尔摩斯
My dear Holmes,
今晚是什么 吗啡还是可卡因?
what is it tonight, morphine or cocaine?
啊 我强烈推荐
Well, I can strongly recommend
百分之七的可卡因溶液
a seven percent solution of cocaine.
你想试一试吗?
Would you care to try it?
算了吧
No, indeed!
我不仅作为朋友 而且作为医生跟你说
I speak not only as your friend, but as a medical man.
你怎么能如此戕害
How can you risk such damage to the great powers
你天赋的卓越能力
with which you have been endowed?!
我难以形容
I cannot tell you
它多么提神醒脑
how it clarifies and stimulates the mind.
是 最后把头脑毁掉
Yes, and destroys it in time!
我的头脑讨厌停滞状态
My mind rebels at stagnation.
给我问题 给我工作
Give me problems, give me work,
给我最艰深的密码
give me the most abstruse cryptogram,
最复杂的分析 我才最在状态
the most intricate analysis, and I'm in my proper atmosphere.
那就能省掉人工的兴奋剂
Then I can dispense with artificial stimulants.
但我憎恨一潭死水的生活
But I abhor the dull routine of existence.
我渴望精神上的兴奋
I crave mental exultation.
因此我才选择这行
That is why I have chosen my own profession,
或者说创造这行
or rather created it,
因为我是世上唯一一个
for I am the only one in the world.
唯一的私家侦探
The only unofficial detective.
唯一的私家咨询侦探
The only unofficial consulting detective.
我办案不求名声
I take no credit in my cases.
工作本身
The work itself,
发挥我特殊能力的快乐
the pleasure of finding a field for my particular powers
才是最高奖励
is my highest reward.
你可以把抽屉合上了
You can close that drawer.
你诊断错了 医生
You have made the wrong diagnosis, Doctor!
兴奋剂在这里
I have my stimulant here.
希望你在乡间过得愉快
I hope you enjoyed your week in the country.
至少让胃口很好
It was good for the appetite.
顺便说 我真希望你打铃叫晚饭了
Incidentally, I do wish you would ring for supper.
这是什么?
What is this?
对 我在等客人
Yes, I must get ready for my visitor.
随早班邮件过来的
It came by the morning post.
讲讲你的观察
Give me your observations.
它没标日期 也没有签名或地址
Well, it's undated and without either signature or address.
很好 大声读
Good, read it aloud.
"亲爱的福尔摩斯先生"
"Dear Mr. Holmes:
"今晚七时三刻 将有"
There will call upon you tonight at a quarter to eight
"某君前来"
a gentleman who"-
天 就差几分钟了 福尔摩斯
good heavens, we've only a few minutes, Holmes.
继续
Go on.
"某君前来商谈"
"A gentleman who desires to consult with you
"至关重要之事"
upon a matter of the very deepest moment.
"阁下近来为欧洲某王室效力"
Your recent services to one of the royal houses of Europe
"证明阁下足堪信赖"
have shown that you are one who may be safely trusted
"可以难以言喻之"
with matters which are of an importance
"重大事务相托"
which can hardly be exaggerated.
"此种传述 广播四方 我等知之甚稔"
This account of you we have from all quarters received,
"届时望勿外出"
be in your chamber then. "
天 还真是神秘啊
Good-good heavens, this is a mystery, indeed.
你想这是什么意思?
What do you imagine it means?
我还没有事实
I have no data yet.
没有事实妄加推测 那是大忌
It is a capital mistake to theorize before one has data.
但就便条本身
But the note itself,
你能推断些什么?
what do you deduce from it?
是男人的字迹
It's a man's writing.
很好
Good.
大概很有钱 这纸很贵
Presumably well-to-do, it's expensive paper, this.
纸质结实挺括得出奇
It's peculiarly strong and stiff.
出奇 正是这样
Peculiar, that is the very word.
这不是英国造的纸
It is not English paper at all.
举起对光看看
Hold it up to the light.
啊 大写的E 小写的g 大写的P和G
Ah, large E, small g, large P, and G
还有个小t 交织在一起
with a small t woven into the texture.
所以呢?
And that is?
制造者的花押印
Maker's monogram.
漂亮 华生
Excellent, Watson!
过来
Come along!
我们来查查
Let us consult our continental gazetteer.
你的雪茄 你瞧 我可没忘了你要回来
Your cigars; you see, I was not unmindful of your return.
哦 福尔摩斯
Oh, Holmes!
来点威士忌吗?
Would you care for some whiskey?
等会 晚餐再说吧
Later, perhaps, when we've eaten.
花押是Papier Gesellschaft的缩写
The monogram is an abbreviation for Papier Gesellschaft,
德文里的"造纸公司"
which is the German for "paper company. "
而Eg Eglow Eglonitz Egria
And the Eg, Eglow, Eglonitz, Egria,
说德语的波希米亚区
a German-speaking district of Bohemia
有大批玻璃作坊
noted for its numerous glass factories
和造纸厂 看
and paper mills, there.
波希米亚 波希米亚王国
Bohemia, the kingdom of Bohemia.
便条是个德国人写的
And the note is written by a German.
你看 "此种传述"
You see, "this account of you
"广播四方 我等知之甚稔"
we have from all quarters received,"
只有德国人这么乱用词句
only a German is so uncourteous to his words.
所以客人是波希米亚的德国人
So we are to expect a German from Bohemia.
他来了
Here he is,
乘漂亮的两驾小马车
drawn by a pair, a nice little brougham.
这案子至少有赚头 如果没别的
There's money in this case, Watson, if there's nothing else.
福尔摩斯 客人来了我还是回避吧
Holmes, I think your visitor will want me out of the way.
绝对不用 医生 呆在这
Not a bit, Doctor, stay where you are!
我可离不开我的传记作家
I am lost without my Boswell.
可他说得那么秘密
But he sounded so secretive.
我可能需要你帮助 他也是
I may need your help, and so may he.
在椅子里坐好 集中精神听
Now, stay in that armchair, and give me your full attention.
他来了
Here he comes.
抱歉 先生
I'm sorry, sir,
你不能就这么闯进来
but you cannot come in here unannounced like this!
福尔摩斯先生不见未预约的客人
Mr. Holmes does not see anybody without appointment!
哦 我很抱歉      福尔摩斯先生
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mr. Holmes!
我拦不住他
There was nothing I could do!
完全没关系 哈德森夫人
It's perfectly all right, Mrs. Hudson!
请您先离开
If you would kindly leave us.
好的
Yes.
关上门
And close the door.
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
你收到信了?
You read my note?
是的 请坐下
Yes. Pray take a seat!
我的朋友和同事 华生医生
This is my friend and colleague, Dr. Watson,
他偶尔好心地帮我办案
who is occasionally good enough to help me in my cases!
您好 先生
How do you do, sir.
请问您怎么称呼?
Who do I have the honor to address?
你可以叫我冯克拉伯爵 波希米亚贵族
You may address me as the Count Von Kramm, a Bohemian nobleman.
我更愿意和您单独谈
I should much prefer to communicate with you alone.
要谈一起谈 要么拉倒
No, it is both, or none.
当着这位先生
You may say before this gentleman
您想对我说的都可以说
anything which you may wish to say to me.
好吧 我暂且信你
Very well, I take your word
当他是谨慎有荣誉的人
that he is a man of honor and discretion.
但我得先跟二位约定保守秘密
But I must begin by binding you both to absolute secrecy
为期两年
for a period of two years.
是吗
Indeed?
期满之后
At the end of that time
这事就无关紧要了
the matter will be of no importance.
目前 它的分量
At present it is of such weight
足以影响欧洲历史进程
that it may have an influence upon European history.
保证遵约
I promise.
我也是
And I.
你们不会介意这面具吧
You will excuse this mask.
我尊贵的雇主
The august person who employs me
不愿让你们见到他的代理人
wishes his agent to be unknown to you.
实际上 我承认刚才所报的
In fact, I may confess that the title I have given you
并不是我真的头衔
is not exactly my own.
这我知道
I was aware of that.
情况十分微妙
The circumstances are of great delicacy;
得不惜一切代价防止丑闻发生
every precaution must be taken to prevent an immense scandal
不然它会严重危及
which would seriously compromise
欧洲王室之一
one of the royal houses of Europe.
坦率说
To speak plainly,
此事关系到奥姆斯坦家族
the matter concerns the great House of Ormstein,
波希米亚世袭国王
hereditary kings of Bohemia.
这我也知道 陛下
I was aware of that, too, your Majesty.
你说得对
You are right...
我就是国王
I am the King.
我何必隐瞒呢?
Why should I attempt to conceal it?
何必呢?
Why, indeed?
陛下尚未开口
Your Majesty had not spoken
我就知道我面前是
before I was aware that I was addressing
威廉・戈特赖・西吉蒙・冯・奥姆斯坦
Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond von Ormstein,
卡赛费坦大公 波希米亚世袭国王
Grand Duke of Cassel-Felstein, and hereditary King of Bohemia.
顺便 也是欧洲决斗之冠
And in passing, the finest dualist in Europe.
您已经杀了四个对手
You have killed four opponents.
很荣誉的
Honorably.
当然
Of course.
简单地说 事实是
The facts are briefly these:
十年前 我到华沙长期访问
Some 10 years ago, during a lengthy visit to Warsaw,
认识了大名鼎鼎的女冒险家
I made the acquaintance of the well known adventuress,
艾琳艾德勒
Irena Adler.
无疑你很熟悉这名字的
The name is no doubt familiar to you.
华生 请拿我的资料索引查一下
Kindly look her up in my index, will you, Watson.
我推断 陛下和这位女士有牵连
So, I deduce that your Majesty became entangled with this lady,
写过几封危险的信
wrote her some compromising letters,
急着把它们弄回来
and is now desirous of getting them back.
一点不错
Precisely so.
但你怎么知道?
But how could you know that?
意大利总目录
Italian general's staff...
啊 艾德勒艾琳 1858年生于新泽西
Ah, Adler, Irena, born New Jersey, 1858.
这位女士?
Is this the lady?
新泽西 我看看
New Jersey, let me see.
女歌手 女低音
Singer, contralto
彼得堡 华沙和斯卡拉歌剧院驻唱
appeared at La Scala, opera houses Petersburg and Warsaw,
已退出歌剧舞台
retired from the operatic stage,
现居伦敦
now living in London,
偶尔唱音乐会
makes occasional concert appearances.
是这位女士
That is the lady.
和她秘密结过婚吗?
Was there a secret marriage?
没有
None.
没有法律文件或证明吗?
No legal papers or certificates?
没有
None.
那我就不明白了 陛下
Then I fail to follow your Majesty.
如果她想用信件来
If this person should produce your letters
进行讹诈之类
for blackmailing or other purposes,
她怎么证明信是真的呢?
how is she to prove their authenticity?
有我的笔迹
There is the writing.
呸 伪造的
Pooh, pooh! Forgery.
我私人的信笺
My private writing paper.
偷的
Stolen.
我的印鉴
My own seal.
仿的
Imitated.
我的照片
My photograph.
买的
Bought.
我们两人都在照片里
We were both in that photograph.
哦 天啊天啊
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
那就糟了
Yes, that is very bad.
陛下的确太不检点了
Your Majesty has certainly committed an indiscretion.
她美丽 迷人 机智 勇敢
She was beautiful, bewitching, clever, daring.
当时我不过是王储
I was only Crown Prince then.
还很年轻
I was young!
现在我也不过30岁
I am but 30 now.
当然 陛下
Of course, your Majesty
也试过收回照片?
has attempted to recover the photograph?
我们试过 失败了
We have tried and failed.
那陛下必须出钱
Then your Majesty must pay.
把照片买过来
It must be bought.
她不愿意卖
She will not sell.
那就偷吧
Stolen, then.
试过五次了
Five attempts have been made.
我两次雇小偷搜遍她家
Twice burglars in my pay ransacked her house.
一次在她旅行时调换行李
Once we diverted her luggage when she traveled.
两次对她拦路抢劫
Twice she has been waylaid.
可都一无所获
There has been no sign of it.
好笑吗?
You mock?!
问题很严重
It is serious!
是
Yes.
确实十分严重
Yes, it is very serious, indeed.
那她要拿照片干什么呢
Well, what does she propose to do with this photograph
如果不是为了勒索?
if not to extort money?
把我毁掉
To ruin me.
怎讲?
How?
我就要结婚了
I'm about to be married.
我听说了
So I've heard.
娶克洛蒂・洛特曼・冯・札克宁根公主
To the Princess Clotilde Lothman von Saxe-Meningen,
斯堪地纳维亚国王次女
and second daughter to the King of Scandinavia.
真是门当户对啊
It is a brilliant match.
正是
Precisely.
你可能知道他们家规严格吧
But you will know the strict principles of her family.
她本人也很敏感
She's herself the soul of delicacy.
只要对我的行为有丝毫怀疑
A shadow of doubt as to my conduct
这婚事就告吹
would bring the matter to an end.
艾琳艾德勒呢?
And Irena Adler?
她威胁要把照片送给他们
Threatens to send them the photograph.
她做得出来
And she will do it.
她的个性坚强如钢
She has a soul of steel.
她有最美丽的女人的面容
She's more beautiful than any other woman I've known,
最刚毅的男人的心
more resolute than any man.
没什么她做不出来的 没有
There are no lengths to which she would not go, none,
只要能阻止我娶别的女人
to prevent my marriage to another woman!
陛下
Your Majesty,
为什么这位女士这么怀恨?
why is this lady so vindictive?
我们...讨论过结婚
Oh, there was once some talk of marriage.
哈
Ha!
她不明白这是不可能的
She would not see that it was impossible!
您敢肯定照片还没送出去吗?
You are sure that she has not sent the photograph yet?
我肯定
I am sure.
为什么?
Why?
也许照片正在路上
It may be on its way at this very moment.
因为她说过她要
Because she has said that she would send it
在订婚公布当天送出
on the day when the betrothal was publicly proclaimed.
就是下周一
That will be next Monday.
可我周五得离开伦敦
But I must leave London on Friday
回国准备婚礼
to be home for the ceremony.
那我还有三天啊
Ah, then we do have three days.
呵 太幸运了
Well, that is very fortunate,
我正好还有别的事
for I do have other matters in hand.
陛下住在伦敦哪里?
Where can I find your Majesty in London?
兰厄姆旅馆
At the Langham Hotel,
名字是冯克拉姆伯爵
as the Count Von Kramm, remember.
是 当然
Yes, of course.
那费用呢?
And as to expenditure?
这是300镑金币 700磅钞票
Here are 300 pounds in gold, and 700 in notes.
艾琳艾德勒小姐的住址?
And Miss Irena Adler's address?
晚安 陛下
Goodnight, your Majesty,
我相信我们不久就有好消息
and I trust we shall soon have good news for you.
福尔摩斯 可以去罗马诺晚餐啦
Holmes, we can dine at Romano's,
可我们只有三天 直到周五
but we only have three days, till Friday.
周五前必须解决
Oh, it must be settled by Friday.
柴可夫斯基
The composer Tchaikovsky
要在圣詹姆士堂指挥他自己的作品
is conducting his own works at the St. James's Hall.
不行不行
No, no, no, no!
周五前必须解决
It must be settled by Friday.
亲爱的华生 我想独自呆一会
My dear Watson, I'd like to be alone.
你饿了?
You are hungry?
是
Yes.
哈德森夫人准有三明治
I'm sure Mrs. Hudson will bring you up a sandwich.
三明治?
A sandwich?
明天下午我们再谈
We will not discuss this matter until tomorrow afternoon.
晚安
Goodnight.
(塞彭泰恩大街)
Serpentine Avenue
(蔓草屋)
Briony Lodge
比干活轻巧 是吧伙计?
Better than working, isn't it, mate?
什么?
What is?
看人干活
Looking on.
真想跟你换换 兄弟
I'll change with you any time, gov.
你干什么的?
And what position are you?
八周 头等马车夫
Eight weeks, a mere first-class groom.
是吗?
Are ya?
你可以帮我一把
Well, you can give me a hand if you like.
我看你不用
I see you're all right.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
只要有酒钱
Give her the price of the booze.
我想也是酒钱
I thought it was the booze.
拴马去 看你能干什么
Strap the mare, show us what you can do.
我跟马夫一伙呆了几个小时
I spent a couple of hours with the cabbie and his cronies.
艾琳艾德勒小姐
Miss Irena Adler
她倾倒了那一带所有男人
has certainly turned all men's heads in those parts.
她是世上最俏丽的佳人了
She is the daintiest thing under a bonnet on this planet,
塞彭泰恩大街马房 人人都这么说
so say the Serpentine-mews fraternity, to a man.
她生活平静
She lives quietly,
每天下午五点出去
drives out at five in the evening,
七点整回家吃晚餐
returns at seven sharp for dinner.
深居简出 只除了演唱
Seldom goes out at other times, except when she sings.
她只有一名男客 可是过从甚密
She has only one male visitor, but sees a good deal of him.
他每天至少来一回 经常是两回
He never calls less than once a day, and often twice.
他叫戈弗雷诺顿 住在坦普尔
His name is a Mr. Godfrey Norton, of the Inner Temple.
这就是跟车夫交朋友的好处
You see the advantages of having a cabman as a confidant.
戈弗雷诺顿先生是律师 这很关键
Mr. Godfrey Norton is a lawyer, that is important.
也许还有些不妙
Ominous, perhaps.
为什么他不断地来?
Why his repeated visits?
她是他的委托人 朋友 还是情妇?
Is she his client, friend, or mistress?
如果他是她的律师
If he is her lawyer,
照片也许在他保险柜里
he might have the photograph to his strong box.
如果是情人 他可能对照片一无所知
If her lover, he might not even know of it.
当时她刚开口唱歌
She had just begun to sing,
她有天使般的歌喉 华生
she has the voice of an angel, Watson,
那时突然发生了一件奇事
when a truly surprising chain of events overtook me,
有人来访
starting with the arrival
我估计是戈弗雷诺顿
of someone I presumed to be Mr. Godfrey Noble.
等我 好吗
Wait for me, will you.
把夫人的马车接进去
Fetch your mistress's carriage.
拚命快赶
Drive like the devil,
去圣莫尼卡教堂 艾薇尔路
Church of St. Monica, Edgeware Road.
最晚十二点差五分要到
I must arrive there at least five minutes before 12:00.
还有20分钟 赶到了赏你半个畿尼
That gives you 20 minutes. Half a guinea if you do it.
她真是明艳动人 华生
She is a lovely woman, Watson,
容貌足令男人倾倒
with a face that a man might die for.
A face a man might die for-
你从没说过这种话 福尔摩斯
unusual language for you, Holmes.
修辞而已 华生 没别的
A metaphor, Watson, nothing else.
我正想赶上去攀在车后
I was just about to sprint after the landau and perch on the back
恰好一辆出租马车经过
when another cab came through the street.
看我衣衫褴褛 有些犹疑
He looked twice at such a shabby fare,
但我在他拒绝之前跳进车里
but I jumped in before he had time to object,
掏出一把金磅
showed him a handful of sovereigns
答应给他一磅
and promised him one
只要20分钟之内赶到莫尼卡教堂
if he would get me to the Church of St. Monica within 20 minutes.
我从不记得
Now, I don't think
坐过这么快的马车
that I have ever been driven faster in a cab.
他们比我们先到
They were there before us.
很抱歉 诺顿先生 但我
Look, I'm very sorry, Mr. Norton, but I-
发发慈悲吧 已经中午了
For pity sake, it's almost midday.
法律规定的最晚时间
The latest time allowed by law.
我可以随便找个牧师来
I would have called in one of those confounded churchmen
但我先前为了不泄密
but I saw no reason to let them know our business
打发他们吃酒去了
and I sent them off for a drink.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, dear Lord!
戈弗雷
Godfrey.
你 过来 伙计
You, you, come here, man!
是 就叫你
Yes, I mean you!
我们只剩几分钟了 否则就不合法
We've only a few minutes left or it won't be legal!
快过来 伙计 过来
Come man, come!
拿着这个 照吩咐的做
Hold this and do as you're told.
我付钱
You'll be paid.
啊 有证人了
Ah, we have our witness.
婚礼开始
The ceremony may proceed.
诸位朋友 我们今天以神的名义聚集一堂
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here in the sight of God
见证这对男女神圣的婚礼
to join together this man and this woman in holy matrimony
这一荣耀的仪式由上帝所创造
which is an honorable estate instituted of God
自从鸿蒙初始
in the time of man's innocency,
为我们代表了上帝
signifying unto us the mystical union
与世人间神秘的联结
that is betwixt Christ and his church.
艾琳
Irena.
我一直听你的
I allowed you to persuade me,
现在你得听我一次
now you must allow me to persuade you.
我明天再见你
I shall see you tomorrow.
第一时间
At the very first moment.
我爱你
I love you.
约翰
John.
嘿 你
Hey, you!
过来 伙计
Come here, my man.
过来
Come here.
戈弗雷 让我来
Godfrey, let me.
先生 我要谢谢你
Sir, I want to thank you
在我们需要你的时候奇迹般降临
for being so miraculously present when we needed you.
有你在近旁是多么幸运
How fortunate that you have remained close by.
反正我也闲着 夫人
Well, I'm in no hurry, mum.
我希望你能接受这个
I hope you will accept this.
我不收小费 夫人
I don't need no tip, mum.
先生 就当是个纪念品
Oh, sir, let us call it a little souvenir.
她赏我一个金磅
She gave me a sovereign.
在这
Here it is.
这也太出乎意料了
What an extraordinary turn of events!
我要把它拴在表链上
I shall wear it on my watch chain
纪念这次的际遇
in memory of the occasion.
现在怎么办?
And what now?
婚礼的时候
Well, during the ceremony
我以为我的计划完了
I thought my plans had been overthrown.
如果他们立刻离开
If they had made an immediate departure,
我就不得不
it would have necessitated
立即采取最强硬的措施
the most prompt and energetic measures on my part.
可他回了坦普尔 她回了自己家
But, he went back to the Temple, and she went to her own home,
因此 我们有时间行动
thus, giving us time to act.
怎样?
How?
医生 我需要你所有的勇气和警觉
Doctor, I shall require all your courage and alertness.
乐意效劳
I shall be delighted!
你不怕犯法吗?
You don't mind breaking the law?
一点也不
Not in the least.
也不怕万一被捕吗?
Nor running the chance of arrest?
只要目标高尚 我不怕
Not in a good cause.
噢 这目标再高尚不过了
Oh, the cause is excellent.
好 我听你的
Well, then I am your man.
好极了
Splendid.
现在 问题是
Now, the- the question is-
福尔摩斯 你这造型太棒了
Holmes, you really do look quite remarkable!
问题是照片在哪里
You know, the question is where to find the photograph.
我是指 房子被搜了两回
I mean, the house has twice been burgled.
她比他们聪明多了
She was too clever for them.
她是个了不起的女人
She is a remarkable woman.
他们一定仔细查找过了
Well, they must have searched very thoroughly.
那是他们不会查
They did not know how to look!
你要怎么查
And how will you look?
我不查
I shall not look.
那怎么办?
What then?
我会让她自己拿出来
I will allow her to show me.
她肯定不答应
But she'll refused.
她不能够
She will not be able to.
啊 快到行动地点
Ah, we draw near the scene of action.
最好下去步行
We had better walk from here.
约好的还记得吧
You know your instructions.
你一举手 我就行动
When you raise your hand, I act.
10分钟后在约定地点集合
And we meet at the rendezvous in 10 minutes.
她来了
Here she comes.
没你份
Oh, no, you don't.
我先来的
I was here first.
我开的门 夫人
I opened the door, lady.
不是他 明明是我
He never, no, it was me!
让开 你们两个
Clear off, you two!
放开我
Let-me-go!
给人开车门
Opening carriage doors
这是合法行当
is a legitimate means of livelihood, Mr. [inaudible].
总得让人赚个铜板吧
You ain't gonna stop a man earning a copper, see.
让我过去
Let me pass.
你们 放开我的马车夫
You there, let go of my coachman!
从我嘴里抢食 你敢
Take the bread from me mouth, would 'ya?
看我塞上你的嘴 小子
I'll fill your mouth, chum.
哦 不要 请住手 伙计们
Oh, no, no, please, please don't, men,
求你们住手 求你们
please, I beg you, please I beg of you!
夫人 我得保护你
Madam, I must protect you!
住手 都给我住手
Now stop that, you and you, stop that.
退后
Stand back!
看你们干的好事
You see what you've done!
他死了
He's dead!
快跑 弟兄们 当心警察
Scamper, mate, before the coppers come!
他还有呼吸 但被敲的很重
He's still breathing, but he's taken a bad knock.
抱歉 夫人
I am sorry, ma'am.
你尽力了 约翰
You did your best, John.
他伤得很重吗?
Is he badly hurt?
只是皮肉伤 但他马上需要人看护
It is only superficial, but he needs attention, quickly.
不能让他躺在街上
But he can't lie on the street.
抬进屋里去
Bring him into the house.
好了 先生
All right, sir.
哦 你醒了
Oh, you're conscious.
谢天谢地 你真勇敢
Thank goodness, you are a brave man.
过来 维罗
Over here, Willot.
不用 我来
No, no, stand back,
我来照看我的患难之交
I shall look after my friend in need.
先生 请转过脸来
Sir, will you look toward me.
这不是女士该看的
Oh, it is no sight for a lady.
我很坚强 我的朋友
I have strong nerves, dear friend.
不不 我不允许
No, no, I cannot permit.
谢谢你
Thank you.
给我绷带
A bandage.
听你的
As you wish.
你的伤没有大碍 我松了口气
I'm so relieved that your wound isn't serious.
伤口不深 头也不晕了
Well, it is but shallow, and the concussion wears off.
真奇怪
How extraordinary.
夫人?
Madam?
这么多人
That so many people
聚在这么个小角落
should gather in such a quiet little turning.
都是一伙的 夫人
Well, it's the gang, madam,
埋伏好了抢劫你
it was all pre-arranged to rob you.
这么多人抢一个小钱包
All those men to snatch one little purse.
不 朋友 这根本不值
Oh, no, dear friend, it wouldn't have paid them.
我的职责让我常常接近穷人
My vocation takes me much amongst the poor
甚至罪犯 夫人
and even the criminal classes, madam.
瞧瞧这些人
Look at those people staring,
好奇心很不体面 但恐怕人人皆有
curiosity is so unseemly, but I fear universal.
真对不起 我觉得要晕倒了
Oh, I am so sorry, I think I'm going to faint.
通气 我要通通气
Oh, air, I need some air!
维罗 开窗
Willot, the window1
哦
Oh!
拿水来喝
Some drinking water.
有没有嗅盐?
Are there any smelling salts?
夫人 夫人 我闻到烟火味了
Madam, madam, I think I can smell fire.
什么
What?
火 火
Fire, fire!
着火了 着火了
Fire, fire, fire!
着火了 是吗?
There's a fire, is there?
夫人 快离开这
Madam, come out of here quickly!
我来照顾老先生
I'll take care of the old gentleman!
我喘不过气来
I can't breathe.
假火警
It's a false alarm!
是假火警 瞧
It's a false alarm, look!
是个陷阱 告诉他们 告诉他们
It's a trick, it's a- tell them-tell them!
着火了
There's a fire!
是假火警 听到了吗
It's a false alarm, do you hear?
我们不需要消防车
We do not need the fire engine!
这是什么?
What is it?
是个烟火筒 夫人
It is a plumber's rocket, madam,
我有个伙计是管子工
one of my flock is a plumber.
顶上点火
It is ignited by a cap,
把烟散到管子里 查找裂缝和洞
and sends smoke into pipes to betray cracks and holes.
不不不 不用了
No, no, no, no, no, it's all right.
会散开的
It will disperse.
你说是个陷阱
You said it was a trick.
谁会这么陷害我呢?
Who would play such a trick on me?
他们一伙的 夫人
One of the gang, madam.
为什么呢 我已经摆脱了啊
But to what purpose? I've escaped them.
报复
Revenge.
报复?
Revenge?
有如此邪恶的人吗?
Are there such wicked people?
这世界上有些人 夫人
There are people in this world, madam,
将报复本身当作乐趣
to whom revenge is in itself a reward.
我无法想像这种感觉
I cannot imagine such feelings.
我相信你不能 夫人
I'm sure you cannot, madam.
呃 我觉得我缓过来了
Well, I am feeling more myself.
我得走了
I must be on my way.
哦 请留下来 吃些点心
Oh, please stay, some refreshment.
有人在等我
Well, one of my flock expects me.
不让我的马车送送你吗?
Won't you let my carriage take you?
不用不用 外面的空气有助于我恢复
Oh, no, no, no, the air will aid my recovery.
至少留下你的名字和地址
At least your name, your address,
让我好好谢谢你
that I may thank you adequately.
唉 我只是个虔诚的仆人 夫人
Well, I am just a humble servant, madam,
侍奉无所不在的天意
of the all seeing providence.
晚安
Goodnight.
你做的很棒 医生
You did it very nicely, Doctor.
你拿到照片了?
You have the photograph?
还没 但我知道照片在哪
No, but I know where it is.
你怎么找到的?
How did you find out?
她拿出来的 我就说她会的
She showed me, as I told you she would.
麻烦的是 还在她那里
The trouble is, it still remains in her possession.
你可能没机会了 福尔摩斯
You may have lost your one chance, Holmes.
不会
No.
我明天早些来拜访
I shall call early tomorrow morning.
你去拜访?
You'll call there?
作为我本人 陪同国王去
And as my own self, and with the King.
国王?
The King?!
你也去 华生
And with you, Watson!
你必须作整件事的见证人
You must be a witness at the end of our quest.
至少你今天能睡个好觉了 福尔摩斯
I trust you will sleep well tonight for a change, Holmes.
成功对治疗失眠最好不过了
Well, there's nothing like success for curing insomnia.
晚安 夏洛克福尔摩斯先生
Goodnight, Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
还有华生
and Watson.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
但她不可能爱上他
But she could not love him.
我希望她有
I am in hopes that she does.
为什么?
Why?
因为这样就为陛下
Because it would spare your Majesty
省去了无穷后患
all fear of future annoyance.
如果她爱她的丈夫 她就不爱陛下
If she loves her husband, then she does not love your Majesty.
如果她不爱陛下
And if she does not love your Majesty,
她何必干涉陛下的婚事呢
why should she interfere with your Majesty's marriage.
是夏洛克福尔摩斯先生吧
Mr. Sherlock Holmes, I believe.
我是福尔摩斯
I am Mr. Holmes.
我们夫人说你大概会来的
My mistress told me you were likely to call.
她和他先生乘五点十五分的火车
She left this morning with her husband by the 5:15 train
从查林十字车站到欧洲大陆去了
from Charing Cross for the Continent.
她离开了英国?
She has left England?
再也不回来了 先生
Never to return, sir.
全完了
All is lost.
好 拿到了
Well then, get at it.
不是这张
This is not it!
福尔摩斯 不是这张照片
Holmes, this is a different photograph!
你听到没 伙计?
Do you hear me, man?!
信拿来
The letter.
是写给我的
It is addressed to me.
"亲爱的夏洛克福尔摩斯先生 干的漂亮"
"My Dear Mr. Sherlock Holmes: You did it very well.
"你完全骗过我了"
You took me in completely.
"直到火警之前 我一点没怀疑"
Until after the alarm of fire, I had not a suspicion.
"但是随后我发觉自己泄露秘密时"
But then, when I found that I had betrayed myself,
"我突然想起"
it flashed into my mind
"几个月前就有人警告我防备你了"
that I had been warned against you months ago.
"据说如果国王要雇侦探"
I had been told that if the King employed an agent
"那一定是你"
it would certainly be you.
"尽管如此"
Yet, with all this,
"你还是使我泄了密"
you made me reveal what you wanted to know.
"即使先前在那么多人聚在街上"
Even before when the presence of so many people in the street
"使我有所警觉"
had sounded an alarm in my instinct,
"我都不曾想到如此可爱的老牧师会有恶意"
I could not think evil of such a dear, kind old clergyman.
"但是 你知道"
But, you know,
"我本人就是训练有素的女演员"
I have been trained as an actress myself,
"男扮女装并不陌生"
and male costume is nothing new to me.
"对 是我尾随你到家"
Yes, it was I who followed you to your door,
"就是来确定"
just to make sure
"你真是著名的福尔摩斯"
that you really were the celebrated Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
"是我冒失地祝你晚安"
It was I who rather imprudently, wished you goodnight.
"接着去坦普尔找我丈夫"
Then I started for the Temple to see my new husband.
"我们秘密结婚"
We had married in secret
"以防万一需要出国躲避国王"
in case we needed to leave the country to elude the King.
"你的出场暗示我们该走了"
Your appearance on the scene was the signal for flight.
"我们无法和你作对"
You are too formidable an antagonist.
"等你明天来时 就会发现房子空了"
You will find the nest empty when you call tomorrow.
"至于那张照片 你的委托人尽管放心"
As to the photograph, your client may rest in peace.
"我爱一位比他强的人 他也爱我"
I love and am loved by a better man than he. "
"国王可以"
"The King may"-
"国王可以随心所欲"
"The King may do what he will
"不必顾虑他所辜负的人会妨碍他"
without hindrance from one whom he has cruelly wronged.
"我保留照片只为了自卫"
I kept it only to safeguard myself,
"留下一件武器 永远保护我"
and to preserve a weapon which will always secure me
"不受他任何迫害"
from any steps he may take. "
还有
There is more.
"我留给他一张他可能愿意收下的照片"
"I leave another photograph which he might care to possess;
"亲爱的福尔摩斯先生 我仍然"
and I remain, dear Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
"诚心向您致意 艾琳诺顿 原名艾德勒"
very truly yours, Irena Norton, nee Adler. "
多伟大的女人
What a woman!
她会成为多伟大的皇后
What a queen she would have made!
真可惜她和我不在一个水平
Is it not a pity she was not on my level.
就我所见
From what I have seen of the lady,
她的水平的确和陛下很不一样
yes, indeed, she is on a very different level to your Majesty.
我很遗憾没能完成使命
I am only so sorry that I have failed in my commission.
恰恰相反 亲爱的先生
On the contrary, my dear sir,
这已经很成功了
nothing could be more successful.
我知道她言而有信
I know that her word is inviolate.
那张照片现在和被烧了一样安全
The photograph is now as safe as if it were in the fire.
我很高兴陛下这么认为
I am glad that your Majesty thinks so.
我对你感恩不尽
I am immensely indebted to you.
请告诉我怎样酬答你才好
Pray, tell me in what way I can reward you.
这个戒指?
This ring?
陛下有件东西
Your Majesty has something
我认为更有价值
which I should value even more highly.
只要你开口
You have but to name it.
这个
This.
艾琳的照片?
Irena's photograph?
当然 如果你愿意
Certainly, if you wish it.
那我谨祝
Then I have the honor
陛下您早安
to wish your Majesty a very good morning.
这就是一大丑闻
And that was how a great scandal
如何威胁着波希米亚王国
threatened the Kingdom of Bohemia,
而福尔摩斯的杰出计划
and how the best plans of Mr. Sherlock Holmes
怎样被一个女人的才智所挫败
were beaten by a woman's wit.
他过去常常嘲笑女人的智力
He used to sneer much at the cleverness of women,
近来再没有听到了
but I have not heard him do it of late.
而当他谈论艾琳艾德勒
And when he speaks of Irena Adler,
或者提到她时
or when he refers to that woman,
总是尊称她为"那位女人"
it is always under the honorable title of "the woman. "
在他眼里 她超越了她的性别
In his eyes, she eclipses the whole of her sex.
他从未流露出任何
It was not that he ever betrayed any sign of love
对艾琳的爱慕
for Irena Adler,
所有诸如那样的情感
all emotions such as that one
都与他冷酷精密的头脑不符
are abhorrent to his cold, precise mind.
他只以病理的眼光看女人
He only looks on women pathologically,
把她们看作动机 线索
as the source of motives, clues.
然而 他留下她的照片 锁起来
And yet, he keeps her photograph apart, locked up.
对他 世上只有一位女人
There is but one woman to him,
美丽的艾琳艾德勒 留在模糊朦胧的记忆中
the beautiful Irena Adler, of dubious and questionable memory.
破烂熊字幕组 -==www.RagBear.com==- 欢迎加入